Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Diners/Fugazy Travel and Incentive Company records, 1970-1975 and undated RL.11154
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Diners/Fugazy Travel and Incentive Company records
1970-1975 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
RL.11154
3.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Diners/Fugazy Travel and Incentive was a short-lived (1970-1976) joint venture between JWT and General Leisure, Inc. offering a range of travel, merchandising and sales incentive programs. It was sold to Thomas Cook in 1976.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
The Fugazy Travel Bureau was a family travel agency established in New York in 1869. William Denis Fugazy became President in 1947 and sold the agency to Diners Club in 1967. Fugazy formed General Leisure, Inc. and bought back part of the Fugazy busines in 1970 and entered into a 50/50 partnership with J. Walter Thompson the same year. The joint venture had two divisions: Executive Incentive, which produced sales incentive programs; and Executive Travel that offered a range of travel services. JWT president Dan Seymour sat on the Board and JWT executive John Devine served as manager.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Diners/Fugazy Travel and Incentive Company records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company Dan Seymour papers; J. Walter Thompson Company John Devine papers; Anspach Travel Bureau Collection of Tourism Literature.
Collection Overview
Collection spans 1970-1975 and includes legal and financial papers, correspondence and memoranda, meeting minutes, clippings, reports and other materials relating to the establishment and operation of the enterprise. Companies represented include Austin Travel, Brasch Associates, Ford, Montgomery Ward, Phillips Petroleum, Reader's Digest, Sunsweet and Travelco, as well as materials relating to William (Bill) Denis Fugazy. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company -- History; Travel agents -- United States; Sales promotion
- Administrative study, Detroit office, 1971; 2 folders (Box 1)
- Alden Press v. Diners/Fugazy Travel, 1971 (Box 1)
- Annual Report, 1970 (Box 1)
- Austin Travel, 1970-1973; 3 folders (Box 1)
- Bob Hope Desert Classic, 1973 (Box 1)
- Brasch Associates, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
- Clippings and press, 1970-1975 (Box 1)
- Company overview, undated (Box 1)
- Concept paper, circa 1970 (Box 1)
- Consumer Sales Motivation for Atlantic Richfield's Credit Card Customers, 1971 (Box 1)
- Controller job description, undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence and memoranda, 1970-1971; 2 folders (Box 1)
- Correspondence and memoranda, 1971-1973; 6 folders (Box 2)
- Data processing proposal, 1970 (Box 2)
- Department store program, 1971 (Box 2)
- Diners Club London Directory 1971-1972 (Box 2)
- Direct mail, circa 1970 (Box 2)
- Direct mail proposal for Phillips Petroleum, 1970 (Box 2)
- Family Fair/Con Edison, 1970 (Box 2)
- Finance (budgets, forecasts, financial reports), 1970-1973; 4 folders (Box 3)
- Ford, 1970-1972; 4 folders (Box 3)
- Ford Autolite, 1970 (Box 3)
- Franchise agreement (generic), undated (Box 3)
- Fugazy Continental, 1973 (Box 3)
- General Leisure, Inc., 1970-1973; 3 folders (Box 4)
- Gold Bond stamps, 1971 (Box 4)
- Incentive Time, undated (Box 4)
- Interim Report, 1970 (Box 4)
- Joint venture agreement, 1970 (Box 4)
- Meetings (agendas, minutes), 1970-1973; 6 folders (Box 4)
- Montgomery Ward, 1971 (Box 4)
- Newsletters, 1973 (Box 4)
- Operational/Procedural and Administrative Analysis, 1972 (Box 5)
- Participating department stores, 1970 (Box 5)
- Proposal for Sunsweet Growers, 1970 (Box 5)
- Proposal to RCA, 1971 (Box 5)
- Reader's Digest, 1971 (Box 5)
- Swans Tours (U.K.), 1971 (Box 5)
- Travelco, 1972 (Box 5)
- United Kingdom/Europe, 1972 (Box 5)
- Catalog, undated (Box 6)
- Civil Aeronautics Board filings, 1972 (Box 6)
- Elegant Collection catalog, 1972 (Box 6)
- Executive Incentive Division brochure, undated (Box 6)
- Finance (budgets, forecasts, financial reports), 1970-1971 (Box 6)
- Fugazy Continental franchise agreement, undated (Box 6)
- Printed material (brochures, etc.), 1971 (Box 6)